Nicholas Llerandi - Web / Software Engineering

linkedin.com/in/nicholasllerandi github.com/nllerandi nick@nllerandi.com 516-476-0318

Summary

9+ years experience thinking "out of the box" and providing well-researched, cost-effective software-based solutions. Strong in JavaScript, Node.js, React, GraphQL. Expert integration problem-solving skills, written and verbal communications as well as business acumen.

Past Industries

Media, AdTech, Telecommunications, Marketing, Web & Software Development, IT, Audio

Skill Highlights

Web/Software Development:

JavaScript, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, React, Redux, HTML5/CSS3, MySQL, SQL, Python

Systems:

Git, Github, Gitlab, Unix/Linux Systems, JetBrains development tools, VSCode, DigitalOcean, AWS / Elastic Beanstalk, Netlify, Jenkins, Google Ad Manager, Tag Management (Tealium, Google Tag Manager, Adobe DTM)

Employment

Rubicon Project / Magnite

Solutions Architect - Apr. 2020 to current **Solutions Engineer** - Apr. 2019 to Apr. 2020

- Headed the development of multiple applications built on Node/React/GraphQL to support engineering and other internal teams.
- Lead technical integrations of Magnite products (Prebid.js) into systems of some of the company's largest clients.
- Act as ongoing lead technical point of contact for internal teams and clients, engineering software-based solutions that streamline processes and positively impact bottom line.

Verizon - Technical Solutions Manager - Nov. 2017 to Apr. 2019

- Engineered internal JavaScript/Node/React applications and systems used for QAing complex taxonomies, simplifying processes and interacting with platform APIs.
- Utilized Google Tag Manager, Tealium, Adobe DTM to managing website tagging, data and analytics
- Drove the technical integration of Visual IQ multi-touch attribution: developed marketing tag logic and implementation strategy that would be used as the foundation of Verizon's MTA reporting.

Verizon - Rich Media Developer - Feb. 2017 to Nov. 2017.

- Developed all dynamic ad templates (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) for use in dynamic ad server.
- Managed digital creative and media trafficking teams, ensuring proper QA, cross-browser performance and accurate data outputs.

Emazzanti Technologies - Project Manager - Sept. 2016 to Feb. 2017

- Setup company Github workflow and continuous integration / automatic deployment pipeline.
- Managed design and web development teams for both B2B and B2C clients.
- Managed international team in the migration of 50+ websites and databases during company acquisition to scalable Azure deployments, ensuring no downtime and full transparency with clients.

Liqui-Site - Digital Project Manager - 2014 to 2016

- Managed 10+ digital marketing and web development projects at any given time, maintaining scope and budget.
- Brought on as first PM in a startup environment, introducing agile concepts allowing for projects to be completed quicker and more efficiently.
- Developed internal profitability tracking system using MongoDB, Express, Node.

Limelabs Design - Remote Contractor - 2012 to 2014

 Contracted on project-by-project basis to manage the design, development and deployment of web-based projects.

Education

Manhattanville College - **Masters** in Marketing Communication Management

Conservatory of Music at Purchase College - **Bachelors** in Music Performance: Jazz Studies

Certifications:

Certified ScrumMaster Scrum Alliance 2015